So in the previous video of Kafka
stream, I have told you about different
sources. KStream like how you can do
that builder.stream
the topic name
and the serializer deserializer.
Similarly, KTable
global KTable. We have already seen that
and their purposes. Okay.
Now
today in this part, I would go one level
deeper into this
Serdes S E R D E S.
So this is nothing but
a combination of serializer plus
deserializer. So S E R D E S.
Okay. So serializer and deserializer
combined into one object. That object is
you can say called as Serdes.
So
we have already covered serialization
deserialization as part of normal
Kafka producer consumer. We have seen
that. So serializer is that
serializer is that which convert Java
object to bytes. Deserializer is that
which convert bytes to Java object.
So Serdes like combine both into one
package.
Now you can ask like what's the need
into the Kafka stream?
So see
the Kafka topic it stores the data in
bytes. The RocksDB it stores the data in
bytes.
So whenever we need to read from the
Kafka topic or RocksDB, we need
deserialization, convert bytes to Java
object. And whenever we have to write
data to Kafka topic or RocksDB we need
serialization, convert Java object to
bytes. You know that right? Topology has
source
processor nodes
sink. So source is like reading from
topic. So you have you need
deserialization capability. Sink is like
writing to Kafka topic. So you need
serialization, convert Java object to
bytes.
Similarly, apply for the RocksDB also.
So, these are the five places in
topology where we need serdes. Serdes.
We need to read from Kafka topic, we
need deserialization.
Sink, we need to write to Kafka topic,
we need serialization.
Repartition, we will see that. So, if
you remember from the architecture
video, I told you about the
sub-topology, which is like a
repartition. We need to write to Kafka
topic, so we need serialization.
Okay, internally it create a Kafka
topic,
so we need a serialization.
Similarly, RocksDB write, so when do you
write into the RocksDB? Like KTable,
global KTable. So, when we write it, we
need serialization, convert Java object
to bytes.
Okay?
Another uh processor nodes also has many
uh methods which writes into the RocksDB
like count, which we will see that later
also.
Similarly, RocksDB read, when do we read
from the RocksDB like join, which is
within a one of the method into the
processor. So, it read from the RocksDB.
So, we need deserialization capability.
So, in short, whenever you have to read
or write from Kafka topic or RocksDB,
you need
serializer and deserializer.
Okay?
So, these are built-in serdes.
So, serdes.string, serdes.long,
serdes.integer, double, byte array,
float, short, boolean. So, these are
inbuilt.
Okay, so it can automatically cover like
string to bytes, bytes to string. So,
serdes is like combination of your
serializer plus deserializer. So, it has
So, you can say that serdes is an object
which has
serializer object,
deserializer object. Okay? So, whenever
it has to write,
it make use of serializer object,
whenever it has to read, it make use of
deserializer object. Okay, that's why I
have used both the array. With the
serdes, you can do both.
String to bytes, bytes to string.
Similarly, serdes.long, long to bytes,
bytes to long, like this.
So, these are the inbuilt serdes which
Kafka Streams provides.
Now,
serdes priority.
So, there are two priority. You can say
that low priority and high priority.
Then the low priority, what comes is the
default serdes.
So, in application.property,
if you give like kaf-
spring.kafka.streams.properties.default.key.serde.
So,
see, everything is a key-value. So, we
need serializer-deserializer for key, we
need serializer-deserializer for value.
So, one is for key, one is for value.
So, in application.properties,
so for key, we have provided that
default key serdes like
serde is string serde.
Like you have provided this a string
serde. Similarly, value serde you have
provided whatever the serde you want to
use out of this. Whichever you want to
use, let's say I'm using a string serde.
So, now we have provided here in the
application.properties.
So, what would happen? What's the
advantage we will get
by applying to the default serde?
Without default serde, what we have
seen, I have see if you have watched the
previous video where in the source,
KStream, KTable.
So, in the KStream is like
builder.stream topic name. So, we have
to read it from here. From read this
topic. So, we have to provide the
serdes like you have to provide the
serializer-deserializer.
From KTable, we have to provide the
serializer-deserializer
because we are reading this topic.
Similarly, in the KTable, we also
maintain a RocksDB, and for RocksDB
also, we have to provide key and value
serializer deserializer.
Similarly, global K table. So, the thing
is, without default serdes, we have to
specifically mention the key serializer
or deserializer or value serializer or
deserializer
every time we cross the boundary, like
we have to read from topic, read from
RocksDB, likewise.
But,
when we do, when we use default, like we
have applied into
application.properties,
this can be your minimal code.
builder.stream, this, that's all. You
don't have to provide this
serializer deserializer.
Similarly, this will go here, this all
things will go here. Okay? So, this will
become your minimal. You don't have to
provide explicitly every time.
But,
this in Kafka stream, this default
serdes is very less frequently used.
Why? Because see, in the Kafka stream,
we have pipeline. You read from source,
then it goes to a processor pipeline,
which does lot of thing, lot of changes.
Ultimately, it goes to the sink.
So, it is possible that the topic
earlier you key was a string, let's say,
value was a string.
But,
so, it's okay for the source. The string
serdes, the string serdes, key value.
But, during processing,
my stream now become like key is a
string,
but value become long.
Like, my agenda would be like
total count
of
orders.
So, now I just change it to the long.
So, now here if you see, if you use
default sort,
it won't work for all scenarios now.
So, only in scenarios where like
whenever any particular boundary does
like in source, we are reading from
topic. In processor, you are reading in
RocksDB. In sync, you are reading in
output topic. Everywhere, you have like
same key value, then you can go for
application.properties.
Otherwise, I would say that never use
default sort in case of a stream because
as part of a stream, it change your data
change a lot.
Okay? So, always use explicit one.
That's what explicit one has the highest
priority. So, if you're reading it
explicitly tell that yes, treat key as a
string, value as a string.
KTable,
treat key as a string, value as a
string. When you're writing into the DB,
your serializer would be a key as a
string, value serializer would be a
string. Likewise, explicitly we have to
tell. And that set is the highest
priority.
Clear?
Okay? So, the same thing. Explicitly we
are writing during source, during sync
also. So, like we are writing into the
topic order.dot2. We are
explicitly telling that produced with
your key serializer and the value
serializer. Use a string a string
serializer.
Okay?
So, RocksDB file. So, explicitly we have
to tell everywhere.
Now, one question might have come. Hey
Shayansh,
got it.
But, the list you have see shown, the
built-in sorts, we have a string, long,
integer, double, bytes, float, short,
boolean. But, what about custom Java
objects? Like, what about I have order,
customer object, countries object. How
to handle those?
So, there is already inbuilt cert, which
is JSON cert.
We can use that.
Now, let's say for example, at this
point of time
I will just show you that what if we
have to write our own this JSON cert.
It's already inbuilt. It's already built
in into the framework. We don't have to
write. But, I will just show you that if
we have to build our own, how to build
that.
So, first step is we have to write a
serializer.
Now, let's say I'm writing a serializer
that JSON serializer
implements serializer class. So, this
serializer belongs to this Kafka common
serialization. serializer. So, we have
to implement this.
Okay? And we have to provide an
implementation for this override method
serialize.
Now, how you want to serialize? That's
the logic here. You have to do that. So,
currently I'm just using simple Jackson.
So, object mapper write value as byte.
That's all.
Whatever the data So, see the my data is
T is of generic type. Here in this
serialize method
this data is of generic type. Okay?
Now, whether you have got a object uh
let's say order
payment, customer, whatever the object,
you can pass it.
That I can just write value as a byte.
So, I can serialize it. Convert the
object to bytes using Jackson.
Okay? I am just returning bytes array.
Now, the second is you have to write
deserializer. So, for deserializer
whatever the class name you have to
give, implement this deserializer class.
Okay?
Kafka.common.serialization.deserializer.
Now, when you have to deserialize means
from bytes bytes array
to Java object. Now, only thing is
we have to tell that whatever the bytes
we are getting in which object type we
have to convert. That's the only thing
extra in the deserialization. We also
have to explicitly tell which object
type. See, in during case of serializer,
we don't have to tell object type
because we are already getting the data.
Whether order object, payment object,
whatever the object, we just have to
convert it to byte.
But when we convert from bytes to
object, we have to tell which object,
okay? So, that's where the target class.
Let's say order.class or payments.class,
which object type you have to convert.
That's the only extra information it
required.
So, we have to provide an implementation
of this override method.
objectmapper.readValue,
whatever the data bytes array, convert
to this target type. Okay? So, target
type is like we will pass it.
order.class, payments.class. So, convert
the bytes array to this one.
Very, very generic. Nothing if you are
working with
day-to-day work with Java, you might
have already written this serializer
deserializer. Like I'm using just normal
Jackson. Okay? So, it has done that. So,
I have written the deserializer also.
Now, I have written the third serde,
combination of serializer plus
deserializer.
So, I've given the name class JSON
serde.
implements this SCRD serde.
kafka.common.serialization.serdes.
Okay? So, we have to just implement
this.
Okay? Now, in this we have
combination of both, serializer, the
JSON serializer we have written.
Deserializer, the JSON deserializer we
have written.
Okay? And when you implement this, you
have to override this two methods.
Serializer method, deserializer method,
where we have to return this objects.
That's all. Nothing else.
All the work is done by this only.
Only thing is this third with the class
which we have created. It's just a
combination of the serializer
deserializer which we have created.
That's all.
And the good thing is we don't have to
write this. It's already present into
the framework. I just wanted to show you
that we can write you can write your own
serializer deserializer if you have some
different logic.
Okay?
So now we have to just use this.
Now let's say we have created this our
own custom third. We can use it.
How we can use it? Let's say a stream
builder. Okay? Now in the builder, you
know that let's say builder.stream. So
I'm using I'm creating a KStream.
Builder.stream, the topic from which I
have to read. Now I have to provide like
read write topic. We have to read from
topic means we have to provide the key
and value serializer deserializer.
So consume with because we are consuming
the data from the topic. Consume with.
What should be the key? Thirds.string.
And the value I am using is order third.
So here I am creating our order third
object.
Okay? New JSON third over class
order.class, the type. So this one.
Okay?
So this is a constructor. We have just
passed the type and this type ultimately
goes to the deserializer.
Yeah.
And ultimately we have this method
internally now framework depend. I am
using consume with.
Okay? So it will make use of that okay,
I have to this use deserializer method
and it will use ultimately invoke this
deserializer method.
Okay? So usage is very simple. Now once
you have created the third, create this
object and pass that
third itself.
Okay? Similarly, when I am producing it
to the output.
Two, we are producing it to this output
topic. Produced with
my key I am using cert. string, but
value I am using as order cert.
Okay, this one.
My custom.
Okay. So, internally it is producing
mean it has to write. So, it will
internally make use of serializer. It
will return serializer object.
Ultimately, it will invoke the
serializer method.
Okay. So, you can write your own
serializer deserializer also.
Now, one more doubt doubt might have
come. Hey, what would happen if
serialization and deserialization fails
in Kafka stream?
So, this is very interesting also. So,
see.
What are the use case when
deserialization can get failed?
So, deserialization means you are
reading from the topic, let's say. You
are reading from the topic.
So, now let's say topic has value this.
Order ID this.
So, this is a JSON string.
But you are reading is at let's say
long.
That will definitely fail.
It won't be able to uh properly
deserialize it.
It tried to read the JSON byte as a
8-byte long. So, it you will get an
exception.
Or corrupted data. Let's say some
garbage bytes that are not a valid JSON.
So, you are trying to read a proper JSON
only.
But the JSON is not correct itself. In
that case also, it won't be able to
parse and exception will come.
So, now the question is what would
happen if deserialization fails?
Serialization also we will see.
So, there are three ways to handle it.
The first is already inbuilt log and
fail exception handler.
So,
see here in this one, there is a class
uh record deserializer.
Okay.
Now, in the record deserializer, here if
you see
deserialize. For each record when you
are deserializing, if any exception
comes, it catch.
Okay? Now, when it catch, handle the
deserialization failure.
Now, it will see.
It is handling.
Now,
there are three ways.
Okay? So, now I will show you first
this, then we'll come back to that one.
The first way is log and fail exception
handler.
This is the default.
So, in application.properties, even if
you don't write it, it would be using
this. Otherwise, explicitly just for
learning purpose,
you can add this like
spring.kafka.streams.properties
default.deserialization.exception.handler
this one.
org.apache.kafka.streams.errors.log
and fail exception handler. This one.
What it do? It will log the error,
throws the exception, your stream thread
dies.
And if all thread dies, your application
Okay?
So, it will not proceed further. So,
let's say your application has
currently, let's say
thread equals to two. So, means two
threads are running. So, if any except
any this thread is running multiple
task,
so if exception comes into this, this
thread gone. If this thread is also
gone, your application dies.
The second one is log and continue
exception handler. Log and continue.
Log the error,
skip the bad record, continue proceeding
the next record.
The bad record is lost forever. So, in
application.properties, you have to just
put log and continue exception handler.
But, I won't uh suggest you that you use
this because you will miss the bad
record
forever.
The third is custom. Like you write your
own exception handler. Now, you decide
what you want, whether you want to
continue, whether you want to fail, or
whether you want to put into dead letter
queue first and then continue.
Now, it's in our hand.
Okay? So, very simple to write it.
So, whatever the class name you have to
give, let's say I've given custom
deserialization handle. You have all you
have to do is you have to implement this
deserialization exception handler class.
Okay? Now, you have to
provide an implementation of this handle
method. Now, whatever you want to do.
So, see, you have a
consumer record, like your record, and
the exception you got.
Processor context is like the same
consumer record information plus
additional information like which thread
is running, which application is
running, some more information.
So, now you can handle like what you
want. So, like I just here
just a demo purpose, I have shown that
I have put an atomic long that error
count. Whenever any error comes, it just
keep on incrementing it.
Okay? When it reach to a particular
limit, max error,
then it will fail, otherwise continue.
Okay? If limit is not crossed, okay, it
continue. It is skip the bad record. But
as soon as limit crossed,
I have to fail it.
Okay? So, deserialization handler
response \dot} fail or \dot} continue.
Now, here if you see
in the code, record deserializer,
you got the response.
Okay? Now, it will check. If the
response is
deserialization handler response \dot}
fail, it will throw exception, stream
exception.
If not, it just drop the record. That's
all. Just continue.
Okay? So, whenever you have to fail
fast, use this \dot} fail. If not, do
continue.
But you can write your own custom logic.
Okay? And there is also one more method
which you can uh you have to provide you
can it can be empty or what generally
this method is like you can read so this
config is like you can read the
configuration and you can update it.
Now let's say I have put it into the
configuration that
stream.max.deserialization.error.
If this is empty
put default 100. Otherwise, whatever the
configuration I have given in
application.property, use that as a max
error and that will I will use it. So
it's just like if you want to read
certain value from the configuration or
you want to change the value.
You can use that. It has all the
configuration value data.
Okay. Generally, it is currently this
method is empty generally. You don't
generally change
but let's say if you want to have
certain like if it is null, have some
default value.
Clear?
Custom is clear, right? And once you
have written your custom class, custom
handler, then all you have to do is
application.properties, you have to just
register it. Like your class path
proper.
Now it will you can use it.
Now in serialization, what does it
means? We are writing.
We have a Java object.
Now we have to write into a bytes form.
So what are the ways it can goes?
Wrong output sort.
So we have long value. Let's say we have
value two
but we are trying to produce with like a
string.
So class cast exception will come.
Order object can't be serialized. So
sometimes what happen is circular
reference. You have an object
uh
reference one points to reference two,
reference two again points to reference
one, so it has a circular reference, so
it won't be able to serialize it
properly. So you will get a mapping
exception. So there are different ways
serialization failure can also happen.
Now there are two ways to handle it.
One is the default one, which is default
production exception handler.
So, it In the default, it always fail.
Your stream thread dies, and if all
thread dies, application dies.
So, in application.properties, if you
don't write it, this will be used.
Otherwise, explicitly also you can write
is
that
org.apache.kafka.streams.errors
default production exception handler.
Okay, any fail
your thread will die itself. If all
thread dies, your like an application
goes down.
Okay?
So, we don't have to write this default
production exception handler. It would
already be there. I'm just showing you
what it might be doing it. So,
it has a class default production
exception handler. It might have
implemented this production exception
handler class.
So, if we have to in future, we have to
write our own custom handler, we have to
implement this production exception
handler.
And it we have to provide an
implementation of this method handle.
That's all.
We have a record which we have to
produce, and also the exception.
Now, in case of this default production
exception handler, we know that it might
be doing
production exception handler
response.fail.
Okay? We don't have to write this just
like what internally it's doing that it
always fail.
But,
I always suggest that write your own
custom handler. Like, if any failure
happen, what you want to do. So, I'm
just showing you some example that
if there is any
event or the record
which is like you it's okay to continue
it without it.
Let's say it's record is too large. You
have or let's say
a particular size of a record. But, if
it is too large,
okay, you will say that continue. Don't
stop the thread itself. But if record is
proper valid,
I am failing the thread itself. Don't
proceed forward.
Okay, so this is just an example. So
custom production handler implements
production exception handler. Okay, we
have to provide an implementation of
this.
It has This method has both producer
record and exception. Now you can do
whatever you want. Whether you want to
fail you, whether you want to continue,
or whether you want to put into some
queue and then continue or fail. Only
these two options are available.
Okay, and also configure like if you
want to read certain property value and
you want to change or not. Generally it
is empty.
So once you have written your custom
handler production handler, all you have
to do is update your
application.properties.
Default production exception handler is
your custom production handler.
Okay, so this will how your
serialization exception would be taken
care.
Clear?
So generally I have covered this topic
just to make sure that we don't have any
doubts with search. Like we are
continuously taking name that consume
with search. dot. string search. dot.
string
during RocksDB also. So there should not
be any doubt like what is search. Okay.
Any doubt, let me know in the comment
section. Now in the next one we will see
different
You can say that our processor
processor nodes like multiple functions
we have, so we will see that.
Okay guys, thank you. Bye.